Mohd Aliff Syazwan bin Mohd Salim

Bayan Lepas, Penang, Malaysia



aliffsyazwansalim@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/aliffsyazwan

Summary

Experienced engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the semi-conductor and automation industry. Successfully deployed machine with internally self-developed control software built from Python. Able to do GUI Programming using Qt tools and familiar with SQL operation.

Experience



Control Engineer

GSH Precision Technology Sdn Bhd

May 2021 - Present (11 months +)

- 1. Design and produce electrical drawing.
- 2. Proficient in PLC Programming (Keyence KV Studio, Rockwell RSLogix5000)
- 3. Onsite technical support for machine modification and setup.
- 4. Setup and configure servo drives and motors.
- 5. Build Control Software based on Open Platform Communication (OPC UA) standard.
- 6. Build frontend GUI using PyQT6 for the Control Software
- 7. Build a database system for the Control Software for machine KPI tracking.
- 8. Integrate SOAP API to the Control Software.



Electrical Technician

LATEXX PARTNERS BERHAD

Mar 2021 - Apr 2021 (2 months)

- 1. Daily record of production line power consumption.
- 2. Maintain 5S in Workshop area
- 3. Execute electrical preventive maintenance on designated production line.

E Engineering Coordinator

Boustead Heavy Industries Corporation Berhad

Feb 2019 - Feb 2021 (2 years 1 month)

- 1. Managed non-conformity report (NCR) and other issues related to ship's design and engineering solution during ship construction by accomplishing 90% NCR closure annually.
- 2. Daily collaborate with project management to accurately inform on on-site execution of engineering solution.
- 3. Directed client and production feedback to the right engineering discipline to minimize impact on project payment claims.
- 4. Co-ordinated engineering issues with ship construction team to timely conclude NCR not more than two weeks.
- 5. Weekly NCR monitoring progress status and target completion to make sure minimal impact on project payment milestone.

- 6. Apply business intelligence analysis to create weekly project progress KPI dashboard and NCR closure report.
- 7. Coded in Python, Excel VBA and Power Query to data mine ship's design progress and provide accurate reporting on project progress milestones using dashboard every week.

Assistant Maintenance Engineer

KESM Industries BHD

Nov 2017 - Feb 2019 (1 year 4 months)

- 1. Formulate maintenance strategy for new tests and carry out repair work within one week.
- 2. Acquire maintenance spare parts and keeping parts stocks replenished on monthly basis.
- 3. Generate weekly report on spare parts inflow and outflow.
- 4. Execute study on new parts to establish component quality up to par with Build-Of-Material list requirements.
- 5. Weekly study on eliminating the production problems from repeating by summarizing breakdown report and provide daily report to Maintenance Engineer for repair process improvement.
- 6. Ensure all daily repair and preventive maintenance are in-line with specification, adhering to strict ESD safety and Standard Operating Procedure related to maintenance.
- 7. To implement daily related activities to meet key performance index of department goals and any other duties assigned by immediate superior.

Maintenance Technician

KESM Industries BHD

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017 (4 months)

- 1. Perform daily electrical and electronic repairs on test instrument's PCB and prioritized compliance with EDS regulation during maintenance and repair job.
- 2. Use digital multi meter and oscilloscope to analyse root cause failure of test board.
- 3. Accomplish daily repair target for test board and execute quality repair activity to minimize impact on production.

General Worker

Subway

May 2017 - Aug 2017 (4 months)

- •Customer service duties include taking orders, answering question, and ringing out customers on the cash register.
- •Kitchen duties include preparing dough, raw ingredients, and kitchen cleaning.

Internship

BHIC Electrical and Technologies SDN BHD

Feb 2015 - Apr 2015 (3 months)

- -Analyse and repair Mass Com Radar Integrated Circuit on chip level using specialise tool.
- -Perform calibration of ship rudder on Navy Class Ship.

Contractor

Estech Marine

Jan 2012 - Feb 2012 (2 months)

-Involvement in marine cable pulling and cable termination of Navy Class ship.

Education

Universiti Tenaga Nasional

Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

2014 - 2017

Technical Elective:

- 1. Control System
- 2. Power Quality
- 3. Elements of Mechatronics
- 4. Data Network Architecture and Electronics

Universiti Teknologi MARA

Diploma Electrical and Electronic Engineering , Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2009 - 2014

Subjects Highlight:

- 1. Industrial Automation
- 2. Industrial Instrumentation
- 3. Process Controll
- 4. Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) in process industry

Skills

AutoCAD • Python (Programming Language) • Programmable Logic Controller (PLC) • Control Systems

Design • Data Collection • Soldering • Waste Management • Preventive Maintenance • Maintenance & Repair • Engineering